<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: word2007 | Liu.Shatle]]></title>
  <link href="http://shatle.github.io/blog/categories/word2007/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://shatle.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2018-04-24T23:13:47+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://shatle.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[liu.shatle &hearts; gmail.com]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[word2007段前段后设置]]></title>
    <link href="http://shatle.github.io/blog/2012/08/17/word2007-duan-qian-duan-hou-she-zhi/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-17T21:13:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://shatle.github.io/blog/2012/08/17/word2007-duan-qian-duan-hou-she-zhi</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>微软官网上Paragraph中有：</p>

<blockquote><p>Public property SpaceAfter Returns or sets the amount of spacing (in points) after the specified paragraph or text column.</p>

<p>Public property SpaceAfterAuto Determines if Microsoft Word automatically sets the amount of spacing after the specified paragraphs.</p>

<p>Public property SpaceBefore Returns or sets the spacing (in points) before the specified paragraphs.</p>

<p>Public property SpaceBeforeAuto Determines if Microsoft Word automatically sets the amount of spacing before the specified paragraphs.</p></blockquote>

<p>实际设置时，直接设置SpaceAfter能成功，但设置SpaceBefore却不成功。搜了一下，没有相关的问题。</p>

<p>仔细看看了API，Paragraph有属性Format， 即ParagraphFormat接口。其中有属性：</p>

<blockquote><p>Public property SpaceAfter Returns or sets the amount of spacing (in points) after the specified paragraph. (Inherited from _ParagraphFormat.)</p>

<p>Public property SpaceAfterAuto True if Microsoft Word automatically sets the amount of spacing after the specified paragraphs. (Inherited from _ParagraphFormat.)</p>

<p>Public property SpaceBefore Returns or sets the spacing (in points) before the specified paragraphs. (Inherited from _ParagraphFormat.)</p>

<p>Public property SpaceBeforeAuto True if Microsoft Word automatically sets the amount of spacing before the specified paragraphs. (Inherited from _ParagraphFormat.)</p></blockquote>

<p>描述基本是一样的。</p>

<p>运行代码：</p>

<pre><code>paraInstance.Format.SpaceBefore = 24;
</code></pre>

<p>但运行此代码就能设置成功。 汗死 ms!!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
